I am a Full Stack Web Developer currently pursuing B.tech in Computer Science Engineering from MSIT, New Delhi. I have worked on projects involving Ruby On Rails, and other website development tools. With some experience, I am really looking forward to work on more projects with various technologies and serve the best in whichever firm I work.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATION				
Course	Institution	Board/Stream	Year	Aggregate
B.Tech	Maharaja Surajmal Institute of Technology, New Delhi	Computer Science Engineering	2013-2017	(4 Semesters) 77.5
12 th	B.M. Public School, Delhi.	CBSE	2013	86.8
10 th	St. Xaviers School, Vapi.	CBSE	2011	9.4 CGPA

WORK EXPERIENCE

YEAR: 2016

• Developed the website of MSIT, New Delhi – Ruby on Rails (Refer: msit.in)

 Chief Organizer of Avensis – Annual Tech fest of MSIT (October 2015 – February 2016)

YEAR: 2015

FeeOnTime Website – Ruby On Rails
 (Refer: feesontime.herokuapp.com)(Freelancing)

 Designed Landing page for Voltaic Power (Refer: voltaicpower.in)(Freelancing)

Competify Website – Ruby On Rails
 (Refer: competifyin.herokuapp.com)(Part of Internship)

- Technical Intern at iLabs.co Startup Incubator (June 2015 August 2015)
- Worked as Coordinator in Avensis Tech Fest MSIT (February 2015 – March 2015)
- Designed Annual Magazine of IEEE MSIT ICON 2015

YEAR: 2014

- Worked as Web Development SIG Head under IEEE MSIT
- Worked as Designer for IEEE MSIT

SKILLS

Ruby On Rails Node.Js HTML CSS JQuery Wordpress SQL Java Bootstrap Adobe Photoshop

AWARDS

Best Volunteer

Avensis

2015

OTHER INFORMATION

Languages known: English, Hindi, Gujarati

English, Hillul, Gujara

Interests:

Basketball, Music, Cars, Gadgets, movies, etc.

DETAILED WORK EXPERIENCE

YEAR: 2016

Website of Maharaja Surajmal Institute of Technology, New Delhi

(Refer: msit.in)

Designed the graphical layout of website and implemented the same using HTML CSS and Bootstrap at the frontend and Ruby on Rails at the backend. I was responsible for development at both the stacks. Also received letter of appreciation from the college.

Chief Organizer of Avensis 2016 – The Annual TechFest of MSIT, New Delhi.

Successfully lead a team of 100 students in organizing the annual techfestival of Maharaja Surajmal Institute of Technology. I was responsible for the technical department consisting of 14 events some of which were Hackathon, Online Coding, AlgoJam, Security Event and 6 gaming events. I also lead a team of 4 students in development of the avensis.in website and the bstorm16.com website. My other duties were making budget, getting sponsors, organizing venues, etc.

YEAR: 2015

FeeOnTime Website - Ruby On Rails

(Refer: feesontime.herokuapp.com)(Freelancing)

Developed the website section named brochure for FeeOnTime using ruby on rails. The website contains listing of all popular colleges, schools and tutions in India. The website contains an admin panel through which all the data is being fed to the database. This project was completed by me in a time span of just 3 days.

Designed Landing page for Voltaic Power

(Refer: volaticpower.in)(Freelancing)

Designed the landing page which consists of a bulb toggling on and off and has various links to the website. Also the page consists of a gallery slider and a news section which fetches news from rss feed.

Competify Website – Ruby On Rails

(Refer: competifyin.herokuapp.com)

Developed the website of competify in using the ruby on rails framework in a team of two members wherein my work was to implement parts of the backend along with the major part of frontend.

Technical Intern at iLabs.co, Startup Incubator in New Delhi

(June 2015 – August 2015)

Worked as a technical intern and got to learn and work with Ruby on Rails. The internship was of two months. I worked on two projects here, competify and shootera. The competify was a competition listing website and shootera was a photography startup.

Worked as Designer & Coordinator in Avensis 2K15 – Technical Fest MSIT

(February 2015 – March 2015)

Worked as Designer in Avensis 2015 which is the annual Tech Fest of MSIT. My work involved efforts in developing the sponsorship brochure along with event posters of several events and the certificates for event heads and event coordinators.

YEAR: 2015

Worked as Event Coordinator of Techvilla in Avensis 2K15 - Technical Fest MSIT

Worked as Event Coordinator of Techvilla which was an event in Avensis 2015. My work involved efforts in bringing participation for the event and organising the event successfully.

Designed Annual Magazine of IEEE MSIT - ICON 2015

Designed the 40 pages annual magazine of IEEE MSIT along with the front and back cover. I worked along with the editorial team and designed the whole magazine myself.

YEAR: 2014

Worked as Web Development SIG Head under IEEE MSIT

Conducted SIGs under IEEE MSIT for web development in which I discussed about the whole procedure of wordpress starting from the installation to seo optimisation. I headed this sig in a team of two members.

Worked as Designer for IEEE MSIT

Worked as designer in a team of four members in IEEE MSIT Designing Team wherein my work involved efforts in designing some of the posters and designing the annual magazine of the society.